A Guide to the Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church Immigrant Oral Histories, 2007: SdArch 30
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church Immigrant Oral Histories
2007
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Zarrugh
SdArch 30
241
.01 cubic feet; 13 cds
Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church Immigrant Oral Histories, 2007, is comprised of sound recordings of interviews of parishioners of the Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church in Harrisonburg, Virginia, regarding experiences of immigrating to the Central Shenandoah Valley. The interviews were conducted by James Madison University students in Dr. Laura Zarrugh's course, SOC395: Immigrants in American Society.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to the Oral Histories is governed by agreements with the interviewees. Pseudonyms were used at the request of the interviewees.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Dr. Laura Zarrugh on June 6, 2007.
Bio/Historical Note
In the spring of 2007, the students in Dr. Laura Zarrugh's course, SOC395: Immigrants in American Society at James Madison University, conducted twenty-two interviews with parishioners at Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church in downtown Harrisonburg, VA. The recordings were made available to Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church for use in conjunction with the church's centennial anniversary celebration. The majority of the interviews were conducted at Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church in Harrisonburg, but several interviews were conducted in the office of William (Chris) Blake at James Madison University, and one interview (Gisel and Nicolas Vazquez) was conducted in the interviewees' home.
Arrangement
Interviews are listed alphabetically by interviewee last name.
Scope and Content
Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church Immigrant Oral Histories, 2007, is comprised of sound recordings of interviews of parishioners of the Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church in Harrisonburg, Virginia. Student interviewers asked the interviewees to talk about their own and their family's experiences as immigrants to the Central Shenandoah Valley. The interviews were conducted by James Madison University students in Dr. Laura Zarrugh's course, SOC395: Immigrants in American Society.
- 30-1: Leogario Alonso, interviewed by Christine Geradi, March 18, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-001)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-2: Yolanda Blake, interviewed by Sarah Midkiff and Lynsey Steele, March 18, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-001)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-3: Alicia, Nataly, and Osiel Bravo, interviewed by Aaron Rossi, March 25, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-002)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-4: Irma Campbell, interviewed by Ryan Tamborini, April 1, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, April 1, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-002)
  - Use copy CD-R, April 1, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-5: Anonymous male, interviewed by Aaron Rossi, March 25, 2007
  Conditions Governing Access
  Full access with pseudonym
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-003)
    Restricted
  - Use copy CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-6: Fernando Cortes Cortes, interviewed by Lynn Brosmer, March 21, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 21, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-003)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 21, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-7: Anonymous male, interviewed by Courtney Robinson, March 25, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-003)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-8: Alfonso Guerrero, interviewed by Ryan Tamborini, March 25, 2007
- 30-9: Gabriela Guerrero, interviewed by Ryan Tamborini, March 21, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 21, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-004)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 21, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-10: Anonymous Male, interviewed by Rachel Repko, March 25, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-003)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-012)
- 30-11: Luz Maria Giron, interviewed by Brooke Boyer, March 18, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-005)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)
- 30-12: Anonymous Female, interviewed by Christine Kahlke, March 21, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 21, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-006)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 21, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)
- 30-13: Enrique Vez Lopez, interviewed by Emily Poly, March 14, 2007
  Restricted; No documentation
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 14, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-007)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 14, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)
- 30-14: Hermila and Manuel Mendoza, interviewed by Allison Brooks, March 18, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-008)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)
- 30-15: Alejandro Olguin, interviewed by Brooke Boyer, March 18, 2007
  Restricted; No deed of gift.
- 30-16: Graciela Pinedo, interviewed by Lynn Brosmer, March 18, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-008)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 18, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)
- 30-17: Salvador Romero Jr., interviewed by Susan Washburn, March 25, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-011)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-009)
- 30-18: Ana M. Sanchez, interviewed by Christine Gerardi, March 25, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-009)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)
- 30-19: Efrain G. Sanchez, interviewed by Christine Khalke, March 25, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-010)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)
- 30-20: Karime Leon Sanchez, interviewed by Courtney Robinson, March 14, 2007
- 30-21: Hoang Truong, interviewed by Allison Brooks, March 25, 2007
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-003)
  - Use copy CD-R, March 25, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)
- 30-22: Gisel and Nicolas Vazquez, interviewed by Sarah Midkff and Sarah Steele, March 31, 2007
  Access Restrictions
  Access restricted; No consent form.
  - Preservation master CD-R, March 31, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-003)
    Restricted.
  - Use copy CD-R, March 31, 2007 (Box 1, Cd-r SA030-OP-013)